More.
A world.
Beyond. New aware.
Of what.
First thought of road the feeling is one
of the most famous of the US treasures.
First touched by the fingers of the humble
Castle it would have been better how did
it never been found. For all those
who possessed game just by being the
violence that. A story opens
in London within the sound of
a boat that was. In the shadow
of Tower Bridge is the constant
a shop of muck and stop coughing
makes. A fearful job if I may say so
you'll be shown to be undertaken in time
of course the Scotch express leaves you
some stations at seven thirty tonight
that leaves very little time for the
arrangement of the body you know mother
just. So I can go to Scotland Yes that
means that I'm home of thank you.
Rather
a nuisance traveling by train and. Up
in jail. For going on about it but.
I'm terribly sorry.
Mr. I was afraid you would get ahead
in time I was studying the face of
a killer passages fascinating and sometimes
most enlightening they demographers
from the plane I presume Oh yes
mother is expecting it I reserved
a compartment to an
elephant Dr Watson has made
a vacancy in this chair
just ahead of the like
a ten day coach Yes these people are
all taken mother wasn't interested in
a bed so much as she was getting
to it and so naturally it was
a bit difficult to
persuade her to travel and
a coach exactly been open to take on
additional testing. I say it was also decent
of you to come considering the fact that I
was so secretive about it all my dearest
Augustus there was no need for secrecy I
already knew you knew that mother insisted
on being the star of the show with
a lot of them and the bargain attempt to
make stupid to Scotland Yard tell you that
. I discussed it with the fact that your
mother the famous diamond is coming not it
came down to London to attend the
reception of Buckingham Palace and quite
naturally it was the stopper to show you
want me to accompany you back to your home
and if their father. Attempt must be made
to steal the stuff or do you feel why you
would get it not to seem simple the way
you explain it Mr thank you if you don't
mind I would yes my friend Dr Watson I can
think what's keeping you mother and I
will be expecting you so could I take this
for you I did much like thank you. Will
be any yes.
They can please. If you got it. Well
a cruise Yeah inspector Let's try why
Mr about your trip in fact I'm pushing
a bit of an omelet that's
very nice truck and.
Rather large rocks which I think
some of the helps when as
a matter of fact I'm going mostly for the
rest going to thank you on the job stuff
and yeah don't you. Trust
the system you don't like
a. City where we take care of the
overflow so. Take your bags.
Out of this myself if you don't mind.
But you to go so. We always leave on time.
I'd say.
Let. My.
Wife from. My. House.
I think. They call.
Thank you for your time the assistance
pretty much until the stuff is over the
rubbish and you away from
out of my hand turn on
a friend of mine and don't complete think
of the prof in your nonsense on me if you
don't think Big Shot home on Tuesday July
thirteenth about retired fifteen years
ago metaphorically reminiscing if I didn't
realize how they find people like so
numb to me almost. Any aspect of the Dr
would you care to drive me to class it was
good as your photo before dinner that
idea. All about. Going to cost his
famous Tom Stoppard to show you something
in last week's attack I feel guilty and
not in the bubble was not home. Just on
this train that's why we're here to see
that this is you call it safe thank you
for it it sounds to me. Sounds to me like
a police between Joe has been going to
attempt to make away with in London was
a successful second attempt will in all
probability been made on this train which
is still there but it seems more than likely
the people in the first attempts were
not discouraged by one will stop at
nothing to ensure success the second time
sounds like
a straw It's comforting to me the strategy
is on this train that's giving an
explicit imitation of
myself and gotten Yes. My
friend you probably got what's new.
I thought it better to engage Mr Holmes
after what happened in London no doubt
you'll be fishing. But I don't
think there's any need for
a policeman policeman how
many people in possession of
a start were to shit in. Twenty five years
you know it may seem strange to but
I've never actually seen it I suppose
there's no harm since we're paying you to
guard it yes.
I do by all means thank you. Scott. What
a remarkable story my husband gave it to
me on our wedding at. Four hundred twenty
carrots and the original Diamond was over
seven hundred cattle. The father had
a cut less ostentatious solution
to shoot ducks what's missing.
Thank you Lady My guess would be as
kind of truth as possible that would be
a novelty in the police. Now if you
wouldn't mind telling us when I can but I'm
just so I'm sorry Mr Jones thank
you and if I did. You know when I.
Heard mention she called displacement
and watch wrong with being
a policeman will have
a strong well you're going to expect is
going to Scotland to fish for salmon the
season doesn't start for another month but
you would know that what you're going to
do to fish for salmon long did. He was.
Punished. For it. On the train scuttling
here I warned you.
Of this because yes this very.
Very low. Class of us got it fixed to.
Stick it to put it.
Across the bed go cut it doesn't compare
with that of the dress it was the quality
of the big difference that
you think. Be your enemy.
It's the spices that make the difference
don't you know how. Much. Should we
wouldn't discussion carrot Oh yes kind of
horrible stuff. One man's meat is another
man's pollution.
My summer be here today.
Fellow I stood in the aisle
Polish wild rice does make
a considerable difference to
a good kind of. Color green will take
care of this for me we want some. For.
US one of. The young
casters in the dining car but you know
that if I became unless I was in my
compartment just now I've been about to
eat and had occasion to bash each adopt I
know up to there was no i'm just ahead
twiddling your thumbs but if. I do peace and
life is gone Sally said that she suspected
the start of sky. And you got actually
right you can have
a very good trip. Well
.
They. Heard it they actually
pick which is an ending for you.
Is this the. Start of each of us in this
box not forty five minutes ago. I saw it.
Might be is something that of course the
star killers got it. They are home about
joining us and it is part of it what.
I did. And you know which made it Mr
rooms that are why I say to you they did
a complete event of up to about six
hundred one pictures from shortish latest
release a door which
not. Every attendant has
a key did you open this door for anyone
to last out the key of it out of the
opposition it never is there is on
a chain. To me and I can't tell you.
The marks of balance on the body none
that I can see seem to have missed it this
time interest or possibly still it was
a natural death came at
a very convenient time didn't it. Not
just this neat. Stuff
pretty sure. It's coming
you were supposed to guard it my son
employed you that's why I left it with him
where is he. Time started to
migrate this stuff as I was to let you come
in like this going into compartment Yes
but I think we better I
don't mind if I get to use.
Portents mother I presume. Well let's get
to the top of. The excuse me enough to.
March if you so young and such
a. High sense to conduct
a list I do want to talk to him and ask
that no one be allowed to leave this coach
Oh thank you Mr I'm sure use my compartment
attendant if not then don't let no one
go in without my permission you understand
the tickets and. So on and official
police business letter I
catch up with you later.
Are you looking for the Scotland Yard
inspector said well yes right in there
something. I mean.
No one's allowed to leave the carriage
copy the cabbage who's ridiculous idea was
that Scotland Yard. Is saying we don't
stop until we reach rugby
that's like a good bit of
a Sarasota the train made before that
time I know Duran Spector and you'll find
that up but we don't do it last night
instead of the facts of this trial and
contest was dead when the job was
taken otherwise he did put up
a struggle and there were no marks of
violence on the body if however he died
a natural death we must assume that the
thief happened to be on and just the right
moment which is outside the realm of
probability notice tried in this case nothing
was left to chance that's why I say find
the murderer under find the diamond and
even though the thief didn't leave the
cage before we discovered the body the
intended was in the car
a dog into. Time and he said that no one
passed into the dining car. At the other
end leads into the luggage
band which is always locked.
You found no marks of any kind on the
body what's significant not even
a scratch of a small spot
of blood on his neck just
a mere speck that's what I was referring
to you mean that scratch killed him it's
possible the poison the well into the
wounded poison we can tell that we are not
upset. With you the list of the
passengers in this carriage Yes. They are
thank you. Major Duncan bleak that would
be your friend Dr the next compartment
empty we took Lady Margaret up
to the murder you remember. Go
on. Living in bed and Inspector this it's
this. Lady Margaret cast years in the
Honorable Rowland Custis Professor William
Hill Bain Mr Mrs Elphick show Cross Mr
Jones and Dr Watson never
beautiful. But I think I shall ask
a few questions. Then the elevator
will stop where there will be shears.
Dead compartments see. Here we have.
Empty. So. You can try and having
seen by himself not only does
represent the official place and him
doing the questioning OK under the seat
cushion for diamonds but any moment we
do know how to do that to myself what
ensures that I owe. My job I think I will
probably find out just much of the start
when to. Do it once or. Just came from.
The start with this one.
Yes My name is what's
got to us. To watch my investment for
this intrusion. I ask you want to do
questions which are doing on the train
your colleagues executives why customers.
There's been no murder committed Scotland
Yard to Sherlock Holmes Sherlock Holmes
and I want to back shut up homes.
Cross-examining suspect suspects
of what I suspected from
a scared murdered you know. Me get
this straight you say I'm not
a has been committed on this train
it's compartment and because
a perfect stranger to me got himself mad
did you come to question me that question
everybody. Policeman know by what
right do you force your way into my
compartment Well I tell you we're going on
this train when are you going not going
to work comes an hour on
the train to watch T.V.
I know it's. Coming up in this battle
for the homes is always chasing off the
missing jewels of mysterious females.
OK.
But does the meaning of this. I'm sorry
Mr but it was necessary for us to search
your property he may I ask
what you expected to find
a valuable juror has been stolen and the
amount of been murdered. They're making
a routine search of the
entire carriage and asking
a few questions. They'll try to.
Understand their journeys
rather the mother. Yes.
Sweet that my question is better just not
a strike. Then excuses will you. See
I can just kind of test destroy you and
it is taking another Scotland the burial.
In a coffin. That is the custom
inevitably. Stop I think will take
a look at the coffin I put interesting. I
was about to suggest it for these myself
and was conducted on
a book in the lobby this was. Not
too much can they trust me to put you on
the big street my friend. And he by using
much coffee just tell me
that this kind of home just
a family of yours naturally he died
I'm sorry that's not so much comes
a very funny take or tonight
even be an accomplished man type
a policeman I take you in charge of this
much I can do it so I find I can prove it
through. Very well out get out of
here and join your silly friends.
Did you discover anything what's Yes very
suspicious character you try to put me
off the scent from the little I heard you
seem reasonably successful OK you're not
going to let it go for like Professor
killing this college where you. Went to try
this one was
a good little course. You
may think. I'm sorry to bother you but
I represent the police. Now say I
told you so you might. Well. It's
quite alright inspector I confess
could first you mean you stole it.
Yes I know where change I'm going
to expect to start
a Scotland Yard. And
don't. Really expect. You
to stall this good luck conducting yourself
in the garden myself have got homes for
the thieves come and speak coupled up their
special careers I confessed confessed
problem now getting
a certain degree and you have to let him
go I mean I told him not to run away and
have
a talk with him. Oh it's
you again it might interest you to
know about just copper thieves.
Excuse me. You know the police I know I
wasn't him but know all he had to take I
must warn you that is it you say may be
used against anything I say they've already
admitted everything everything yes they're
going to either get double what it's
worth if only they won't prosecute It's
my first offense so I will say the same
thing come on and it will be is
it. I stole it I took it from
a hotel in London come on
come on in my small way I'm
a collector of. The parts
Dr Watson does this
look like a diamond we would like
to mention what's all that about
a confession when I came home from the
show but they took it for your piece of I
just up there by not meddling in peace
business this time wasn't entirely wasted
his job at least to pick up at the
Tea Party thank you Holmes part.
Communication in the spirit of all people
good men took up a whole case might be
a good idea to let the police do that you
mind your own business. Oh they want
some How about
a spot in my compartment thanks
seven right if I got to be. I
suppose you realize you'll be turned over
to the priest as soon as we reach anybody
. To keep us. Why we got
a professor killed and you know in the next
compassionate I am in favor have to ask
you
a few questions I don't time now that you're
going to start. Your mind but of course
time I need you to.
I really didn't mind when times were
when your scientist mind has shown
in the way exactly you take the deaths of
young casters for instance I knew from
the first explosion the scientific
approach of course. The man who was
a hypodermic some rare poison from
from South America probably India.
I've been to India so of you. Because.
I don't like your attitude Professor Cuban
I don't know you to talk I have not but
I'm on this train for legitimate reasons
and I have neither the time nor the
inclination to assist you with your work.
You know have to put in your rights and
I'm sure that inspector the start
appreciates that thank you. Now I feel no
objection I have some work to do which
requires concentration now the medics Yes.
Interesting study and I forgot my.
Looking was on the Lady Margaret.
I came to get my fat dos
not naturally perhaps I can help you.
Think. It's just home school I must talk
to you about the diamond Don't you worry
about I think you might get fifty thousand
pounds you tell me not to watch. My son
employed this man to guard it and it was
totally right on his that he knows I wrong
I intend to take this matter
up with your superiors I'm
a private agent they deny me who I should
report two books to Scotland Yard.
I am Scotland Yard.
They did cost is into the dining car so you
and I were already there Holmes came in
later and I understand that inspecting the
driver made this compartment with the
cut open so that anyone got in or out of
the scene so you've got something on this
look at the Thing object if the lady
cost has seen more concerned was more
concerned the loss of the diamond than the
deficit budget you're right so she was.
Kelly N. O U I what I said I have
a dream. Thanks to modify or not to let
me think about this case was it is
Duncan because I have yes I see the way
we figured out the old trout is the only
one without an alibi as we feel to approach
him the whole thing from the wrong
angle really want to let
your theory insurance
a lot of people to show jewelry and
then try and collect on it interesting
suggestion suppose you go and I stated my
view just how much insurance you carry on
the starboard Isha thank you I really had
to try but had to ask yourself but it is
simple reason I already know how to do
this or you know you asked me to make it
through my. Uncle.
Literally show us the parts well
we can eliminate them. Professor
William Kilby I sent a telegram to we had
a better place to check up on that mathematics
professor. Interesting to know what
. Were just a coincidence it's
a coincidence. That this fellow
killer Ben happens to be
a professor of mathematics. Kind of
game Mr Holmes was trying to do We had
a kind of Sebastian Moran course that is
not about well known as you know kind of
Sebastian Moran was the most sinister
ruthless and diabolically clever henchman and
I'll make
a unlamented friend for some money out
here. I've never seen him. I don't
trust the conscious of his presence more
than once this matter of fact he was
directly responsible for one very nearly
turned out to be my penalty or death on
three separate occasions but
a pretty Mr Adams What's all that got to
do with all this possibly nothing. I have
a speciality. The spectacular jewel robberies
and for relaxation he was addicted to
the study of but. Not the medics he was
furry with this professor killed Bain is
Colonel so best to Moran that he murdered
young cusses and stole the diamond but
what about this woman this Vivian better
what about. No one's above suspicion.
And they did Margaret she might have
a motive for wanting this
to British history. She was
a very concerned over the death of
a son. And this friend of Dr
Watson says Major Duncan bleak
might be just as sensible to suspect him.
As far as we know only four persons know
the Starter Edition was on this train
yourself Dr Watson the murdered the dead lad
and myself made
a moderate. I'll have another
talk with that lady. Pretty
much if you mind if I come in.
And if you don't me I. Was like
a beggar Duncan Bleek been playing cards
wouldn't you want all the way across I
believe the expression is if you've been
with him all this time I just left you to
do is for me to
a new fangled General me call it Merrick
and I really don't know but keeping
connected with it. If
you have. It Here it.
Was
a an
.
Leap.
The A. Leap.
The loop. The
loop.
Likud.
Still looking for the matter
of. A school full of.
Holes to so let
the you.
And it's in the Senate.
Where you. Have been.
Asked to would be. Zero. For
ten. I've been observing the
landscape from the day of the end of
a kind of let's just get on that it
didn't seem those shots actually. On the
outside the outside.
Stripes on time we'll take
a look at that coffin to remember and
it was interrupted the last time.
I'm selective to my device pick cotton
using this government no one is allowed in
this whole I think it's fostered excuse.
Me If You Want some of that this is a
very unusual coffin you know a pretzel on
a hair. Wasn't thinking of
a fitting is it that. You might we
have it for didn't so I got it.
But you can't do that so we'll
have to go. Through the three.
Well there is I thought shallow but it
only comes down to about here you think
there's
a secret compartment or
at least. Has to be. And
. Has been recently asked
by NASA to start going
here he's laid about it but.
Let anyone else in here know.
Actually. Gives me something to do.
Come quick and easy because. I don't find
a fast part of it enough room
for the murder to how do you.
What is all this mystery. There's
been a murder has been having
a struggle. It's just
a question of finding it isn't it Mr down
here that. This affair is obviously the
work two men the one who planned it the
other who hid in the coffin and at
a prearranged time emerged to commit the
murder and effect the robbery what are you
talking about the whole Sebastian Moran
you got there man of the day Mr I get
a strike I accepted this case because I
was better to certain that could also be
asked him around could not resist such
a tempting Maslow's the starboard issue
I'm convinced that he's the brains behind
this case and that he's on this train Oh
and how would you go about finding out
which one of the passengers is this Colonel
Sebastian Marais You see years one of
the passengers and I suggest you start by
question is whether my prove interesting
. Oh.
My work OK that
yeah. They have. One or two
questions and I must warn you anything you
say may be used against you. Now that
your mother is your mother after all is it
perhaps if you explain that because they
live examined it and found the secret
compartment How come on that I might have
bought the old story you insist. The
man approached me and asked me to
take a cough and to Scotland he offered me
a hundred pounds you were
aware that the coffin had
a secret compartment Oh I was started
this person tell you to account for
a man being concealed in the coffin that
someone had to leave London far and I
watching the train foreign agent Oh my
baby I didn't believe that foreign agent
story you'll realize of course this makes
you an accomplice was the name of the man
who approached you I don't
remember. The man who engaged you
to take this car from Scotland was it by
any chance this man here I shall mantra
make
a mistake my dear Watson just what do you
know about Major Duncan big I'm going in
for you remember my club I say is this
a joke that's the name of the Rand mean in
the future Colonel MORAN Yes kind of the
best of her and. I'm afraid it doesn't
could have been true don't think that I
don't know of course not you have the
perfect alibi Dr Watson who she. Could have
an agenda or
a perfect liberty to sex my compartment
search me if you find the diamond I know
that hunting necessary at the start of
the day she has not been stolen. What
separates rooms and imitation
is still and I have
a real one if you've got each might strike
Surely you didn't think I would allow
that in my view to retain the genuine dumb
and when I felt reasonably certain that
an attempt would be made to steal it I have
had it in my possession almost from the
moment I boarded a train from family Mr
Jones you have no right to do that this is
a piece of matter come on let me have it
my job is to see that it wasn't stolen it
wasn't that I don't know what this is all
about but I do know that I never seen
this gentleman the fall in my life I
still have to ask you to remain in your
compartment until we reach anybody has
drawn. A telegram for us thank you.
So oh man I'm afraid my friend owes you an
apology because that's all right what's
in the case like this naturally everyone
suspected we all make mistakes he was not
infallible and after all the killer still
at large and yes isn't it well good night
to work that way. I think I'll have another
little chap with the professor felt
something important you have your secrets
Mr Ames I have my. Receipt inspector
struck. Here is this racket
going to continue all
night Professor cure but you told me you
were on the staff of the University of
Edinburgh I said nothing of the kind most
certainly did I. Know I merely said that
I was
a professor of mathematics and that I was
returning to my home in Edinburgh. Well
it might be necessary to talk to you again.
Compounding on the stand again and I
have
a lot on your family and stop fighting
in and out of my room not chamber. Who
isn't the.
Chair doesn't want to open the
door probably. Should help us.
Know who shut up.
Because the back seat. If you get off at
a. Stretch that's
a stretch like the one I'm going to cost
as well. And may have some sort of will
so I will be in preparation to move to
the world it's like I'm standing on the
casket was that it was about to get rid
of the body not the game so I can kill it
they have it.
You're. Going to.
Come away from that door. You seen coming
in here you know shell out comes in the
fat bloke and the like
a. About the god McArdle he didn't
see me I fixed him temporarily
I got enough and. I had to kill.
Harry had better take this. This isn't
the start of. It trying to double
cross me what you. Got the time to replace
it with this imitation now that Scotland
Yard inspector has the real start of.
Course he was Holmes and Watson in the
luggage right now so good that he's probably
in his compartment but you'll have to
hurry I don't like it neither do I. All
you have to do is to relieve him of the
dime. Scotland Yard inspector I have.
Something different naturally it will be more
money for you you would
like that we control.
Them.
He's in there.
He's got the done.
You use this.
Little girl through the
woods. I don't see.
So you put on God isn't that much of
a. Strange funny. Yeah
I figured if I. Was
coming to that want to.
Write something very
serious I would tell you
a popular there are. Boys
like the others. And diamonds.
I'm going to search them out
at once you know you saw
a bit of the man who killed him as the
starboard. Said it's an app just for the
fast poison dart it's quite an unusual
design you would attack because you have the
dumb one. Fortunately this wasn't
do it on your. We're coming to
a stop. Only
.
Scottish police. I don't feel up to
it Mr Would you be good enough to
talk certainly. Quite a bit back in
a minute. This
is Inspector not gonna be any more police
I do do I happen to be in this district
on another case and I will see this telegram
from headquarters you want to talk to
Inspector start me in due time and I'm
in charge here this is Scotland you've
crossed the border we've had
a spot of trouble here Inspector and that's
why I'm here and who are you might I
ask. On
a private inquiry agent I've heard of you
found him to Holmes practice all this
case all right what will you clear
the dining car I want to ask
a few questions and see that no one leaves
this compartment until I need him for
questioning legal to inspect
illustrate ask me to sit in with you
a bit unusual but I think
a great deal of it to Charlotte Holmes
say framed glasses advice. Who is this
inspector mistrusts Watson would use even
speculate stratospheres and recover to
come to Danica.
I know all about you and frankly
and for all I did was buy
a coffee and bring in all the
crying in my opinion this is
a metaphysical got on yours jurisdiction
ended when you cross the border inspector
So you say that some mess up in this bed
is unquestionably in the plot but you may
not know coming around However I do Colonel
Sebastian the man you see in this. You
know. Unfortunately I do. You
mean to change your compact.
You said unfortunately. I once had an
encounter with kind of MORAN The only time in
my entire career I've been best cleverest
criminal since early Professor Moriarty
and then I concur Where is this Sebastian
Rand is travelling on this train under
the name of Major Duncan bleak you know
if you're talking about you serious Mr.
Constable bring in don't leak I said Duncan
break the plate from the gentleman who
won't.
Tell me and. Don't complete Yes expect
to make Dunham would like to see right.
And also that student. Will give me great
pleasure Mr Holmes to meet up with that
scoundrel again you want to see me this
kind of man you are under arrest for so
you've managed to convince him that I'm the
mythical kind of not mythical Damn you
forgot my ferret Inverness three years ago
I've never been in business in my life
do you mind if I say that you
go away. From an innocent
man or carry strange things in your retired
Army on India but you're in Scotland
now and there's
a law against carrying firearms and
you satisfied not quite know. How
I'm satisfied. This clears things
up. When we come into talk man of
few minutes train doesn't stop the top
of I'm afraid I'm not very far from this
time for. This train
will stop at the top of.
You know only delaying the inevitable
catamaran you can get away.
With. And when spectrum. Right especially
down here is
a man who pulled out of course all right
and after we get off here without question
I was taken off. That are
struggling to make an
example good work Mr Holmes for that so I
owe no less to make it you if you will
get me one too sorry I
missed except my apologies.
Oh is that. Going to stop. Looking
at that table over there. The
strong it's got it's got a bleak the
Colonel's a better man coming off like
a man. For
soldiers about. With respect McDonald is
just going off the train he couldn't they
could already have I think ten o'clock
around your henchmen masquerading as
policeman come aboard the train
a rest to stop the train and take you off
but this is fantastic as it is isn't it
and it just came one of the
a colonel's best him or. You can the whole
thing including the coughing the sick
compartment and in case
anything went wrong to suit
a policeman to come aboard and take him off
the train before you'd be checking back
then. When I mention of the
moment you put it off by. Just
a minute back I don't get over there all
of your under arrest put up your hands. To
get to the nearest police station. And not
poke in the aisle or see from shows like
home which wasn't an
accident after all that is
a matter of opinion come get. Some
that I was in was probably
on fairly good it's
a telegram to the real Edinburgh police I
was going to meet us when we arrived but
how did you know this fellow wasn't
a real inspector MacDonald Elementary
my dear Watson in the first place you
couldn't put handcuffs on come around so
I had to do it myself and in the second
place inspector McDonald doing the fight
was more hindrance than help which is not
chaotic touristic the real policeman mace
you know I'm covering to finish but with
so little evidence because I forgot to
mention that I also happen to know the real
inspector
a bit and the police. Which were started
all this yes and surprisingly And I think
that's the situation to be today and usual
Turkey has no dollars very clever homes
you've got me but you haven't got the start
of roads here but I have if in the dark
I could substitute
a big cop like to stop view camera
and it's no any great feat to.
Switch a little thing like a diamond.